let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: " Which of the following physical quantities do not have any unit of measurement?",
        answer: "B. Specific gravity",
        options: [
            "A. Universal Constant of Gravitation",
            "B. Specific gravity",
            "C. Tension",
            "D. Plancks constant"

        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "What is the work done by centripetal force in case of Uniform Circular Motion?",
        answer: "B. 0 joule",
        options: [
            "A. 1 joule",
            "B. 0 joule",
            "C. Depends on the magnitude of Force",
            "D. none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "Which of the following has an effect on the value of acceleration due to gravity?",
        answer: "D. All of the above",
        options: [
            "A. Shape of the earth",
            "B. Height above the earth surface",
            "C. Axial rotation of the earth",
            "D. All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "What is the time period for a satellite orbiting close to the surface of earth?",
        answer: "A. 84.6 minutes",
        options: [
            "A. 84.6 minutes",
            "B. 84 minutes",
            "C. 42 minutes",
            "D. 24 hours"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "The Kinetic energy of a satellite is maximum in which of the following conditions?",
        answer:  "A. when the satellite is at perigee",
        options: [
            "A. when the satellite is at perigee",
            "B. when the satellite is at apogee",
            "C. it is equal at perigee and apogee",
            "D. none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "Which of the following statements is correct?",
        answer: "B. Longitudinal stress occurs only in solids",
        options: [
            "A. Bulk stress occurs only in liquids",
            "B. Longitudinal stress occurs only in solids",
            "C. Both a and b",
            "D. none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "What is the ratio of normal stress to the volumetric strain within the elastic limits is called as?",
        answer: "A. Bulk Modulus",
        options: [
            "A. Bulk Modulus",
            "B. Young Modulus",
            "C. Modulus of Rigidity",
            "D. None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "What is the shape of meniscus when angle of contact is greater than 90Â°?",
        answer: "B. Convex",
        options: [
            "A. Concave",
            "B. Convex",
            "C. Plane",
            "D. None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "Which of the following intermolecular forces enables us to write on the blackboard with a chalk?",
        answer: "B. Adhesive force",
        options: [
            "A. Cohesive force",
            "B. Adhesive force",
            "C. Both A and B()",
            "D. None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "Which of the following is the unit of Strain?",
        answer:  "D. none of the above",
        options: [
            "A. Newton",
            "B. kg",
            "C. Watt",
            "D. none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "What is the force that is required to produce unit elongation in a wire known as?",
        answer: "D. Force constant",
        options: [
            "A. Bulk modulus",
            "B. Thermal strain",
            "C. Thermal stress",
            "D. Force constant"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: "What is the property of a liquid due to which its free surface tries to have minimum surface area?",
        answer: "C. Surface Tension",
        options: [
            "A. Viscosity",
            "B. Buoyancy",
            "C. Surface Tension",
            "D. Rigidity"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: "What is Reynolds number?",
        answer: "A. Ratio of inertial force to viscous force",
        options: [
            "A. Ratio of inertial force to viscous force",
            "B. Ratio of weight of fluid to viscous force",
            "C. Ratio of velocity gradient to viscous force",
            "D. reciprocal of viscous force"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "Which of the following is correct about transverse mechanical waves?",
        answer:  "B. They can travel through solids but not liquids",
        options: [
            "A. They can travel through solids and gases",
            "B. They can travel through solids but not liquids",
            "C. They can travel through solids and liquids",
            "D. They can travel through gases but not solids"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: "In which of the following the sound cannot travel?",
        answer:  "D. Vacuum",
        options: [
            "A. Solids",
            "B. Liquids",
            "C. Gases",
            "D. Vacuum"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: "What are the lines joining places of zero declination known as?",
        answer: "B. Agonic",
        options: [
            "A. Isoclinic",
            "B. Agonic",
            "C. Aclinic",
            "D. Isogonic"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: "Which of the following metal foils was used in the Rutherfords alpha particle scattering experiment?",
        answer: "B. Gold",
        options: [
            "A. Copper",
            "B. Gold",
            "C. Silver",
            "D. Aluminium"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        question: "What is the minimum number of logic gates in a VLSI?",
        answer: "C. 1000",
        options: [
            "A. 10",
            "B. 100",
            "C. 1000",
            "D. 10000"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        question: "Which of the following is true about working of a photo diode?",
        answer: "A. It is operated under reverse bias",
        options: [
            "A. It is operated under reverse bias",
            "B. It is operated under forward bias",
            "C. Both a nad b",
            "D. none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        question: "Which of the following have the same unit ?",
        answer: "C. Work and torque",
        options: [
            "A. Work and power",
            "B. Torque and moment of inertia",
            "C. Work and torque",
            "D. Torque and angular momentum"
        ]
    }
]
